<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>org.manasource.Mana</id>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">org.manasource.Mana.desktop</launchable>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-2.0</project_license>
  <name>The Mana Client</name>
  <summary>A 2D MMORPG client</summary>
  <developer id="org.manasource">
    <name>The Mana Developers</name>
  </developer>
  <description>
    <p>
        The Mana client is used for playing The Mana World and similar online games
        based on either tmwAthena or Manaserv.
    </p>
    <p>
        The Mana World (TMW) is a serious effort to create an innovative free and
        open source MMORPG. TMW uses 2D graphics and aims to create a large and diverse
        interactive world.
    </p>
  </description>
  <url type="homepage">https://manasource.org/</url>
  <releases>
   <release version="0.7.0" type="stable" date="2025-08-21">
     <description>
       <p>Major update! This release brings back the Mana client as a viable client for playing both The Mana World and its spin-off Source of Tales. It has been ported to SDL 2, ships with two additional UI themes and packs a tremendous list of new features to support the current versions of tmwAthena and Manaserv.</p>
       <p>Graphical updates have been made as well, featuring Windowed Fullscreen support, V-Sync and variable-time logic updates to play smooth on displays with high framerates. There is also automatic scaling to support HiDPI displays and improved quality of outlined text rendering.</p>
       <p>As the first major release in 13 years, it is of course not perfect. Any feedback is welcome! Maybe you'd like to join the development of this open source classic?</p>
     </description>
   </release>
   <release version="0.6.1" type="stable" date="2012-04-08">
     <description>
       <p>This release fixes a few annoyances and other small bugs. It is now
       easier to click beings that are close to other beings, NPC trading has
       been removed from chat (again), the last emote can now be used and ring
       and necklace slots were unswapped. Also, the Finnish, Brazilian
       Portuguese and Polish translations were updated.</p>
     </description>
   </release>
  </releases>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://www.manasource.org/gfx/mana-screenshot-2025-08-21-hurnscald.png</image>
      <caption>Peaceful village of Hurnscald</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://www.manasource.org/gfx/mana-screenshot-2025-08-21-mines.png</image>
      <caption>Fighting in the Mines</caption>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1">
    <content_attribute id="violence-cartoon">mild</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="violence-fantasy">mild</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="social-chat">intense</content_attribute>
  </content_rating>
</component>
